Welcome to the suck.
Jarhead is a drama, war film directed by Sam Mendes.
Jarhead is a film about a US Marine Anthony
Swofford’s experience in the Gulf War.
After putting up with an arduous boot camp, Swofford and his unit are sent to the Persian Gulf
where they are eager to fight, but are forced to stay back from the action.
Swofford struggles with the possibility of his girlfriend cheating on him, and
as his mental state deteriorates, his desire to kill increases.
Anthony Swofford, played by Jake Gyllenhaal.
Staff Sgt. Sykes, played by Jamie Foxx.
Alan Troy, played by Peter Sarsgaard.
D.I. Fitch, played by Scott MacDonald.
Lt. Col. Kazinski, played by Chris Cooper.
Ramon Escobar, played by Laz Alonso.
Jarhead is a 2005 biographical war drama film based on the 2003 memoir of the same name by Anthony Swofford,
chronicling his military service in the United States Marine Corps during the Persian Gulf War.
Directed by Sam Mendes, the film stars Jake Gyllenhaal as Swofford with
Jamie Foxx, Peter Sarsgaard, Lucas Black, and Chris Cooper.
Universal Pictures released the film November 4,
2005 to mixed reviews from critics.
It was a box-office disappointment, grossing $97
million against a $72 million budget.
Named for the military slang among U.S.
Marines, the film spawned a direct-to-video series of three
subsequent films, none of which are related to the original.
The film explores themes of california, gulf war,
saudi arabia, petrol, marine corps.
The tone is emotional.